You've seen the logistic regression model.
在上个视频里 你看到了逻辑回归模型
You've seen the loss function
你看到了损失函数
that measures how well you're doing on the single training example.
损失函数可以在单一训练样例上衡量效果
You've also seen the cost function
你也看到了成本函数（同代价函数）
that measures how well your parameters w and b are doing on your entire training set.
成本函数可以在你的全部训练集上衡量参数w和b的效果
Now let's talk about how you can use the gradient descent algorithm
现在我们讨论如何使用梯度下降法（gradient descent）
to train or to learn
来训练或者学习
the parameters w and b on your training set.
在你测试集上的参数w和b
To recap
总的来说
here is the familiar logistic regression algorithm
这里有一个我们已经熟悉的逻辑回归算法
And we have on the second line the cost function  J
在第二行我们看到了成本函数 J
which is a function of your parameters w and b
成本函数J有参数w和b
And that's defined as the average.
并且定义为平均值
So it's 1 over m times the sum of this loss function
因此计算从1到m的损失函数之和
And so the loss function measures how well your algorithms
损失函数可以衡量你的算法的效果
outputs y-hat(i) on each of the training examples
在每一个训练样例都输出y^(i)
stacks up or compares to the ground true label y(i) on each of the training examples.
在每一个训练样例上与真实的标签y(i)进行比较
And the full formula is expanded out on the right
完整的公式在等号右边展开
So the cost function measures how well your parameters w and b are doing on the training set
因此成本函数可以衡量你的参数w和b在训练集上的效果
So in order to learn the set of parameters w and b
要使得参数w和b的设置变的合理
it seems natural that we want to find w and b that
make the cost function J(w, b) as small as possible
自然地想到要去找到使得成本函数 J(w, b)尽可能小所对应的w和b
So here's an illustration of gradient descent
接下来给出梯度下降法(gradient descent)的说明
In this diagram the horizontal axes represent your spatial parameters w and b
在这个图中横轴表示你的空间参数w和b
In practice w can be much higher dimensional
在实践中w可以是更高的维度
but for the purposes of plotting,
但是为了更好地绘图
let's illustrate w as a single real number and b as a single real number
我们定义w和b都是单一实数
The cost function J(w,b) is then some surface above these horizontal axes w and b
成本函数J(w,b)是在水平轴w和b上的曲面
So the height of the surface represents the value of J(w,b) at a certain point
因此曲面的高度就是 J(w,b)在某一点的值
And what we want to do is really to find the value of w and b
我们所想要做的就是找到这样的w和b
that corresponds to the minimum of the cost function J
使得对应的成本函数J值是最小值
It turns out that this cost function J is a convex function
我们可以看到 成本函数J是一个凸函数(convex function)
So it's just a single big bowl
像这样的一个大碗
so this is a convex function
因此这是一个凸函数
and this is opposed to functions that look like this
并且这与看起来像这样的函数相反
which are non-convex
它是非凸的
and has lots of different local optimum
并且有很多不同的局部最优
So the fact that our cost function J(w,b)
因此我们的成本函数J(w,b)
as defined here is convex
之所以定义为凸函数
is one of the huge reasons why we use this particular cost function J for logistic regression
一个重要原因是我们使用对于逻辑回归这个特殊成本函数J造成的
So to find a good value for the parameters
为了去找到参数更好的值
what we'll do is initialize w and b to some initial value
我们将会做得就是用一些初始值来初始化w和b
maybe denoted by that little red dot
可能是用那个小红点表示的
And for logistic regression almost any initialization method works
对于逻辑回归几乎所有的初始化方法都有效
usually you initialize the value to zero
通常用0来进行初始化
Random initialization also works
随机初始化也有效
but people don't usually do that for logistic regression
但是对于逻辑回归我们通常不这么做
But because this function is convex
但是因为函数是凸函数
no matter where you initialize
无论在哪里初始化
you should get to the same point or roughly the same point.
你应该达到同一点或大致相同的点
And what gradient descent does is it starts at that initial point
梯度下降法以初始点开始
and then takes a step in the steepest downhill direction
然后朝最陡的下坡方向走一步
So after one step of gradient descent
因此在梯度下降法一步后
you might end up there
你或许在那里停止
because it's trying to take a step downhill in the direction of steepest descent
因为它正试图沿着最陡下降的方向走下坡路
or as quickly downhill as possible.
或者尽可能快地下坡
So that's one iteration of gradient descent
这是梯度下降的一次迭代
And after two iterations of gradient descent you might step there
两次迭代或许会到达那里
three iterations and so on.
三次等等
I guess this is now hidden by the back of the plot until eventually
我猜想这是隐藏在曲线后面
hopefully you converge to this global optimum or get to something close to the global optimum
希望你收敛到这个全局最优值或接近全局最优值
So this picture illustrates the gradient descent algorithm
所以这张图片说明了梯度下降法
Let's write a bit more of the details
让我们多写一点细节
For the purpose of illustration
为了更好地说明
let's say that there's some function
让我们来看一些函数
J(w) that you want to minimize,
J(w)是你想要找到其最小值
and maybe that function looks like this
可能函数会看起来像这样
To make this easier to draw
为了更容易去画
I'm going to ignore b for now
我现在忽略b
just to make this a one-dimensional plot instead of a high-dimensional plot
仅仅是用一维曲线代替多维曲线
So gradient descent does this
梯度下降法是这样做的
we're going to repeatedly carry out the following update
我们将重复执行以下更新的操作
We're going to take the value of w and update it
我们更新w的值
going to use colon equals to represent updating w
使用：=表示更新w
So set w to w minus α times and this is a derivative dJ(w)/dw.
设置w为w-α dJ(w)/dw(公式如图)
（dJ(w)/dw表示函数J(w)对w求导）
I will repeatedly do that until the algorithm converges
在算法收敛之前我会重复这样做。
So couple of points in the notation
我要说明公式中的两点
α here is the learning rate
首先在这里的α表示学习率(learning rate)
and controls how big a step we take on each iteration or gradient descent
学习率可以控制我们在每一次迭代或者梯度下降法中步长大小
We'll talk later about some ways by choosing the learning rate α
我们之后讨论如何选择学习率α
And second this quantity here this is a derivative
其次在这里的这个数是导数
This is basically the update or the change you want to make to the parameters w
这就是对参数w的基本更新或者改变
When we start to write code to implement gradient descent
当我们开始编写代码来实现梯度下降
we're going to use the convention that the variable name in our code
我们将使用代码中变量名的约定
dw will be used to represent this derivative term
dw表示导数
So when you write code you write something like
因此你会像这样编写代码
w colon equals w minus alpha times dw
w：=w-α dw(公式如图)
And so we use dw to be the variable name to represent this derivative term.
我们用dw作为导数的变量名
Now let's just make sure that this gradient descent update makes sense
现在我们确保梯度下降法更新是有意义的
Let's say that w was over here
我们看w在这
So you're at this point on the cost function J(w)
对应的成本函数J(w)在曲线上的这一点
Remember that the definition of a derivative
记住导数的定义
is the slope of a function at the point
是函数在这个点上的斜率
So the slope of the function is really the height divided by the width
而函数的斜率是高除宽
of a low triangle here at this tangent to J(w) at that point
在这个点相切于 J(w)的一个小三角形
And so, here the derivative is positive.
在这里导数是正的
w gets updated as w minus a learning rate times the derivative
w通过w自身减去学习率乘导数来更新
The derivative is positive and so you end up subtracting from w
导数是正的所以你每一次从w中减去这个乘积
you end up taking a step to the left
接着每一次都向左边走一步
And so gradient descent will make your algorithm slowly
像这样梯度下降法会使你的算法渐渐地
decrease the parameter if you have started off with this large value of w
减小这个参数w 如果在一开始你参数w的值就非常的大的话
As another example if w was over here
另一个例子 如果w的位置是在这里
then at this point the slope here of dJ/dw will be negative
这个点处的斜率将会是负的
and so the gradient descent update would subtract α times a negative number
并且梯度下降法在更新参数时 w将会减去 α乘上一个负数
And so end up slowly increasing w
并慢慢地使得参数w增加
so you end up making w bigger and bigger with successive iterations and gradient descent
因此你会用一个成功的迭代和梯度下降法来 使得参数w越来越大
So that hopefully whether you initialize on the left or on the right
无论你初始化的位置是在左边还是右边
gradient descent will move you towards this global minimum here
梯度下降法会朝着全局最小值方向移动
If you're not familiar with derivates or with calculus
如果你不熟悉导数或者微积分
and what this term dJ(w)/dw means
你也不熟悉dJ(w)/dw的含义
don't worry too much about it
不要着急
We'll talk some more about derivatives in the next video
在下一个视频我们会讨论更多的知识关于导数
If you have a deep knowledge of calculus
如果你深入了解过微积分
you might be able to have a deeper intuitions about how neural networks work
你应该可以对神经网络如何工作有更深刻更直观的认识
But even if you're not that familiar with calculus
但是即使你并不熟悉微积分
in the next few videos we'll give you enough intuitions about derivatives and about calculus
通过下面的几个视频 我们也会对导数和微积分有足够直接的认识
that you'll be able to effectively use neural networks
你将能够有效的使用神经网络
But the overall intuition for now
但是现在所有的直观认识
is that this term represents the slope of the function
便是这个术语 表示的是函数的斜率
and we want to know the slope of the function at the current setting of the parameters
并且我们知道 函数的斜率用在当前的参数设置处
so that we can take these steps of steepest descent
据此我们可以采用下降速度最快的步长
so that we know what direction to step in
我们也可以知道 下一步更新的方向
in order to go downhill on the cost function J
为了可以在成本函数J上走下坡路
So we wrote our gradient descent for J
因此目前对于J的梯度下降法 我们写出来的
if only w was your parameter
只需要w是你的参数就好了
In logistic regression, your cost function is a function of both w and b.
在逻辑回归中你的成本函数是一个含有w和b的函数
So in that case, the inner loop of gradient descent, that is this thing here
在这种情况下 梯度下降的内部循环 就是这里的这个东西
this thing you have to repeat becomes as follows
你不得不像这样重复
w:=w-α dJ(w,b)/dw
b:=b-α dJ(w,b)/db
So these two equations at the bottom are the actual update you implement
这两个等式是你实际更新参数时进行的操作
As an aside I just want to mention one notational convention in calculus that
另外我想提到的是 在微积分的符号约定中
is a bit confusing to some people
对一些人来说是有点困惑的
I don't think it's super important that you understand calculus
我不认为目前理解微积分（符号约定）是非常重要的
but in case you see this I want to make sure that you don't think too much of this
如果你看到这些 希望你不要想太多
Which is that in calculus this term here
在微积分中在这的术语
we actually write as fallows of that funny squiggle symbol
作为这一有趣的花体标志我们实际上这么写
（如图所写的是偏微分符号,读作round）
So this symbol this is actually just a lower case d
所以这个符号这实际上只是一个小写d(即d是偏微分符的小写)
in a fancy font in a stylized font for when you see this expression
当你看到这个表达式的时候 用一个花哨的、样式化的字体
all this means is derivative J(w,b) or really the slope of the function J(w,b)
所有的含义都是J(w,b)的导数或者函数J(w,b)的斜率
how much that function slopes in the w direction
也即是函数在w这一点的斜率是多少
And the rule of the notation in calculus
在微积分中这个符号的规则
which I think isn't totally logical
我认为并不是完全符合逻辑的
but the rule in the notation for calculus
同时对于微积分中这个符号的规则
which I think just makes things much more complicated than you need to be
我认为这样规则会导致更加的复杂
is that if J is a function of two or more variables
也就是指 是当函数J有两个以上的变量（使用偏导数符号）
then instead of using lowercase d you use this funny symbol
我们不使用小写字母d 而使用更加花哨的符号
This is called a partial derivative symbol
这个就称作偏导数符号
But don't worry about this
但是别担心
and if J is a function of only one variable, then you use lowercase d
如果J只有一个变量就是用小写字母d
So the only difference between whether you use this funny partial derivative symbol
唯一的区别就是你是用偏导数符号
or lowercase d as we did on top
还是小写字母d
is whether J is a function of two or more variables
是取决于你的函数J是否含有两个以上的变量
In which case, you use this symbol,the partial derivative symbol
变量超过两个 你使用偏导数符号
or if J is only a function of one variable then you use lowercase d
如果你的函数只有一个变量你就使用小写字母d
This is one of those funny rules of notation in calculus that
这是在微积分上一个有趣的符号规则
I think just make things more complicated than they need to be
我认为它使事情变得更加复杂了
But if you see this partial derivative symbol
但是如果你看到了偏导数符号
all it means is you're measure the slope of the function
其含义就是计算函数关于其中一个变量
with respect to one of the variables
在对应点处 所对应的斜率
And similarly to add here to the formerly correct mathematical notation in calculus
类似在这里 这里的微积分符号正式地写的话 应该改用另一个数学符号
because here J has two inputs not just one
因为在这里J有两个输入参数而不是一个
This thing at the bottom should be written with this partial derivative simple
屏幕底部的这个东西应该用这个偏导数来写
But it really means the same thing as almost the same thing as lower case d
但是这真的表达了和小写字母d同样的事情
Finally when you implement this in code
最后当你编写代码想要实现
we're going to use the convention that this quantity
我们屏幕写出的这个式子时
really the amount by which you update w
通常在更新w的值的时候
will denote as the variable dw in your code
我们会用dw这个变量来代替这个式子
And this quantity, right?
同样也有下面这个式子
The amount by which you want to update b
当你想去更新b的数值
will denote by the variable db in your code
我们将会用db这个变量来表明下面这个式子
All right, so, that's how you can implement gradient descent
综上 这就是梯度下降法的实现方法
Now if you haven't seen calculus for a few years
如果现在你已经很多年不看微积分了
I know that that might seem like a lot more derivatives in calculus
我知道有很多的导数在微积分中
than you might be comfortable with so far
比现在讲的看起来舒服得多
But if you're feeling that waydon't worry about it
如果你有这种感觉 也不要担心
In the next video, we'll give you better intuition about derivatives
我们会在下一个视频中 给你更多关于导数的解释
And even without the deep mathematical understanding of calculus
甚至不通过深度数学知识来理解微积分
with just an intuitive understanding of calculus
而是通过直观来理解微积分
you will be able to make neural networks work effectively
你可以是神经网络变得更加有效
So that, let's go onto the next video
让我们进入下一个视频
where we'll talk a little bit more about derivatives
来讨论导数